# TAEWOON KIM

Al Researcher & Engineer



aewoon.kim

✓ tae898@gmail.com

**y** tae898

github.com/tae898

**m** Google Scholar

in /in/tae898 /// /c/tae898

#### **SUMMARY**

I love diving into AI stuff! I'm both a researcher and engineer in the AI world. It's like finding the sweet spot between brainstorming new ideas and making them actually work in real life. I believe figuring out and improving artificial general intelligence is super important for all of us. I'm all about open-sourcing projects because it's the best way to make AI better together.

#### SKILLS AND INTERESTS -

**Research:** Artificial General Intelligence

Languages: Python, C++, C, Java, JavaScript, Shell

Script, HTML, CSS

Frameworks Pytorch, TensorFlow, OpenCV, NumPy,

/Libraries: SciPy, Flask, Jupyter Notebooks

Platforms: Docker, Linux, GCP, AWS

#### PROJECTS

Al Large Language Models https://taewoon.kim/projects/llm.html

Large language models

Al Computer Vision https://taewoon.kim/projects/computer-vision.html

Computer Vision

Al A Machine With Human-Like Memory Systems https://taewoon.kim/projects/human-memory.html

A Machine With Human-Like Memory Systems

Al Tracking Glass Bottles With Letter in the Sea https://taewoon.kim/projects/glass-track.html

Tracking Glass Bottles With Letter in the Sea

#### EDUCATION

## 2020 - 2024 PhD. Artificial Intelligence, Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam, the Netherlands

Titled "A Machine With Human-Like Memory Systems". This machine is equipped with an external memory system, modeled with a knowledge graph, and uses reinforcement learning to learn essential human skills, such as managing memory, reasoning, exploring, etc.

2015 - 2018 M.Sc. Computer Science, Hamburg University of Technology, Germany

Focused on deep learning and computer vision. Wrote M.Sc. thesis "One Shot Learning for Object Recognition in Pick and Insert Applications" in collaboration with ABB.

2008 - 2015 B.Sc. Electrical Engineering, Yonsei University, South Korea

Focused on digital signal processing and computer vision. Wrote B.Sc. thesis "Obstacle detection for the blind in C++ with OpenCV". The lengthened period of study includes 2 years of mandatory social service.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

2020 - 2024

#### Al Researcher, Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam, the Netherlands

- · Part of the PhD program.
- Carried out research in AI encompassing NLP, Computer Vision, Reinforcement Learning, Knowledge Graphs, etc., most of which can be found on my GitHub and Google Scholar.
- Taught computer programming courses, e.g., Python, and AI courses, e.g., board games with search algorithms and machine learning.
- · Supervised B.Sc. and M.Sc. theses.

2018 - 2020

# **Computer Vision Engineer, Nect, Germany**

- · Worked with machine learning (mostly deep learning) to improve ID card and self verification processes.
- · Mostly dealt with speech, image, and video data.
- Working at a start-up has enabled me to work closely with DevOps and Front-end developers and to better understand the big picture of Al companies.

### 2018 Intern and M.Sc. Thesis Student, ABB, Germany

- Applied robot vision with a RGBD camera.
- Trained computer vision deep learning models, e.g., ResNet, to extract features relevant for robotic pick and place skills.
- Used both RobotStudio and Robot Web Services based on RESTful APIs to interact with both virtual and real robot controllers.